

23 years

Research Assistant

I am currently a student of Data Science in his last semester with interest in the research and academic field and would like to prepare for a Master degree in Computer Science for Science.

My experience in the research field is of 3 years as research assistant with one research internship in Brasil, 3 international conferences with proceedings, 2 national conferences and 1 international poster. This is why I want to keep contributing in the academic field by following a Master program in France and working with a professor to learn new topics like Ontologies, Data Indexing and advanced topics of Data Mining and Text Mining.

l.canovasquez95@gmail.com Av. Juan de Aliaga 449 Lima, Perú

COMPETENCES

Programming Languages: Python, Java, Matlab, Scala.

Web Programming: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript (JQuery)

Data Bases: UML, SQL, phpPGAdmin,

NoSQL

KNOWLEDGE

Programming: Object Oriented, Web, Parallel, Functional.

Data Science: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Mining, Natural Language Processing.

Mathematics & Statistics: Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Algorithms, Complexity, Multivariate Calculus, Modeling, Inference.

FEATURED PUBLICATIONS

Data Mining Algorithms for Risk Detection in Bank Loans. 5th International Conference on Information Management and Big Data, 2018.

Smart City Park Irrigation System: A Case Study of San Isidro, Lima - Peru. 12th International Conference on Ubiquitous Computing and Ambient Intelligence UCAmI, 2018.

Monitoring of air quality with low-cost electrochemical sensors and the use of artificial neural networks for the atmospheric pollutants concentration levels prediction. 5th International Conference on Information Management and Big Data, 2018.

Library data management: a new method to analyze borrowing behavior5th International Conference on Information Management and Big Data, 2018.

LANGUAGES

English:

OOOOOOOOO TOEFL Score 98/120

Portuguese:

000000000

Independent Level

LANGUAGE

FORMATION

2013 - 2018 Universidad del Pacífico, Lima Perú BSc in Data Science

> Featured Courses: Advanced Programming, Data Bases Management, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Big Data.

2002 - 2013 María Reina Marianistas School

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

"Research Assistant" Universidad del Pacífico

2016 - 2018 Supervisor: Ph.D. Alvaro Talavera Lopez

Research Activities: Deep Learning in Finance, High Performance Computing, Smart Irrigation System, Mega-projects carbon footprint assessment in Latin America using decision support systems, Credit Scoring, Data visualization, Air Pollutants Forecasting, Twitter Sentiment Analysis, Electric Energy Forecasting.

RESEARCH INTERNSHIPS

"Research Assistant" Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro

2016 - 2017 Supervisor: Ph.D. Marco Aurélio Fagundes Albernaz

Natural language processing for text recognition, pattern recognition and text classification tasks using Deep Learning.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

TECHO

2012 - 2014 Volunteer for 2 years, TECHO is an ONG that seeks to overcome the situation of poverty that thousands of people live in Latin America by constructing houses for the most needed.

HOBBIES

Basketball in Primary, High School and University - 13 years

Chess in High School and University

Trekking, with many experiences around the Peruvian andes

Outdoor Climbing

Coding Challenges - Finalist in several contests